VANESSA NÚÑEZ PEÑAS

Data Analyst

Data Analyst with experience in machine learning and academic research. Engaging communicator skilled in crafting stories to deliver powerful outcomes for diverse audiences. Enjoy working in a team, being in contact with clients, and overcoming obstacles and challenges contributing to effective decision–making.

10249, Berlin +49 176 85667390 vanessa.nupe@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> <u>GitHub Repositories</u> <u>Tableau Public</u>

Click here for my portfolio

Data Analysis Projects

- **Airbnb Berlin:** Developed market research, utilizing supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms and geospatial analysis with Python and Tableau. Check it out here.
- **Instacart:** Created a targeted marketing project, cleaning, wrangling, aggregating, analyzing, and visualizing data with Python. Check it out here.
- Rockbuster Stealth: Completed an online streaming project, utilizing relational database management and queries with SQL and visualizing the results with Tableau. Check it out here">https://example.com/html/>ht
- Influenza in the U.S.: Conducted a seasonal staff prediction with Excel and Tableau. Check it out here.
- **GameCo:** End-to-end analysis with Excel covering historical sales to foster a better understanding of how new products might fare in the market. Check it out here.

Relevant Work Experience

Machine Learning Data Associate

Amazon Development Center Germany GmbH June 2017 to October 2023 (6 years, 4 months)

- Supported the complete Natural Language Understanding pipeline of Alexa in Spanish and German to improve the understanding, the answers, and the text-to-speech of the devices.
- Coordinated different workflows and verified processes, increasing the quality by up to 98%.
- Ramped new team members by preparing and delivering training and working sessions to ensure high quality since the onboarding.
- Person of contact regarding privacy issues working with the data from customers.

Lecturer of Contemporary History

Complutense University of Madrid July 2009 to July 2013 (4 years)

- Sourced and analyzed thousands of documents archived in five countries with quantitative and qualitative methods and presented the results at international conferences and publications.
- Coordinated seminars and conferences involving students and professors of different universities and research centers.
- Reviewed articles and other documents before their publications, providing feedback to the authors and ensuring the quality of the texts.
- Representative of the researchers in the Faculty Board.

Other Work Experience

- Freelancer Spanish Teacher, Berlin, September 2016 to June 2020 (4 years).
- Tourist Guide, CultourBerlin, November 2014 to October 2016 (2 years).
- **Head Teacher**, Ecus Educational, Madrid, January 2014 to July 2014 (7 Months).

Relevant Skills

- Data mining, wrangling, analysis, annotation, visualization, and database queries
- Python, Jupyter, Pandas, Numpy, Matplolib, Seaborn, Bokeh, Plotly, Dash, Folium, Geopandas, Geoplot, scikit-learn
- SQL, Postgres, pgAdmin4
- Tableau
- Jira, Confluence, AWS
- · Microsoft Office

Education History

Certificate in Data Analytics

CareerFoundry
Graduated in February 2024

PhD Contemporary History

Complutense University of Madrid.

Graduated in September 2013 Summa Cum Laude

Interuniversity Master's Degree in International Relations and Diplomacy

Diplomatic School of Spain Graduated in June 2009

Languages

- . Spanish: mother tongue
- English: full professional proficiency
- German: full professional proficiency
- French: limited working proficiency